Guide to the Victor Lloyd Butterfield Papers, 1910 - 1975
Victor Lloyd Butterfield Papers 1910 - 1975
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Butterfield, Victor Lloyd
1000-319
65
143
The professional papers of Wesleyan's eleventh president, Dr. Victor Lloyd Butterfield, include correspondence, reports, meeting minutes, appointment calendars, speeches, newspaper clippings and photographs. The majority of the material makes up the administrative records of his time as President of the university, but also includes some material from his childhood, time as Director of Admissions at Wesleyan, and post-retirement. A small section of the materials are those of Katharina Geyer Butterfield, Victor's wife.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Acquired in 1967, 1973, and 1976. The items found in Boxes 154-155 came from the Office of Public Information and Publications in 1981 June.
Biographical Note
Dr. Victor Lloyd Butterfield (1904-1975) served as Wesleyan University's eleventh president from 1943-1967, the longest-serving president in Wesleyan's history. Butterfield was born on February 7, 1904, in Kingston, Rhode Island, to Kenyon L. Butterfield and Harriet Millard. He married Katharina Geyer on June 11, 1928 and they had two children, Margot and Daniel.
As a child, Butterfield always wanted to be a teacher, his own father being the president of Rhode Island State College and later Massachusetts State College. Butterfield attended Deerfield Academy before moving onto Cornell where he graduated from in 1927 and later received a master's degree in 1928. In 1936, he earned his PhD from Harvard.
After teaching at independent schools and universities, Butterfield arrived at Wesleyan in 1935 as director of admissions and instructor in philosophy. Butterfield quickly progressed to Dean of Freshmen in 1938, Associate Dean in 1941 and Acting President in 1942. After a one-year stint as acting president of Wesleyan, he was inaugurated as president in 1943 and remained as such until his retirement in 1967.
During Butterfield's tenure at Wesleyan, he increased the size of the student body, the number and quality of faculty, number of buildings on campus, and the endowment fund. Butterfield also changed the curriculum to meet the demands of returning WWII soldiers, and through his dedication to liberal education he created the highly acclaimed and innovative "College Plan", established the Center for Advanced Studies and laid the framework for the re-establishment of a co-educational Wesleyan.
Butterfield, a nationally-known spokesman for liberal education, was a member and at times leader of many organizations and societies such as the Ford Foundation for Advancement of Education, and the Commission on Liberal Education of the Association of American Colleges. His involvement with such organizations and societies continued on after he retired from Wesleyan. He earned honorary degrees from 14 institutions.
Collection Overview
The professional papers of Wesleyan's eleventh president, Dr. Victor Lloyd Butterfield, span from 1910-1975 with the bulk of the material from Butterfield's time as President from 1943-1967. The papers include correspondence, reports, meeting minutes, appointment calendars, speeches, newspaper clippings and photographs. Aside from the administrative records, the papers include some material from Butterfield's childhood, his time as Director of Admissions at Wesleyan, his involvement in professional activities and his post-retirement life. A small section of the materials are those of Katharina Geyer Butterfield, Victor's wife.
Collection Arrangement
The original order of these records has been maintained. Some areas contain groupings of records that are Butterfield's personal, professional activities or post-retirement records rather than administrative records during his time as president:
Boxes 68-88 include personal and professional activity materials.
Boxes 90-95 include personal materials.
Related Material
President's Office Records (Collection #1000-180)
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Butterfield Papers1910-1975
  - [Student] Comments (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - [Student] Letters (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Comments from '49 graduates (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Comments from '51 graduates (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Comments from '51 graduates (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Comments class of '54 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Comments '55 graduates (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Student reports '57-'58 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - [Student] Comments (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Commencements (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Commencements, October '45 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Commencement and honorary degree material (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Commencement and honorary degrees awarded (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Commencement & honorary degrees (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Commencement and honorary degrees (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Commencement & honorary degrees granted (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Commencement (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Commencement and honorary people (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Commencement and honorary degree people (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Commencement (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Commencement & honorary degree recipients June '56 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Commencement (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Commencement June 1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Commencement (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Honorary degrees (not voted) nor accepted (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Commencement (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Commencement (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Commencement (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Honorary degrees (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Commencement (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Commencement (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Commencement (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Departmental reports (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Departmental reports (Box 6, Folder 6-9)
  - Departmental reports (Box 7, Folder 1-9)
  - Departmental reports (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
  - Departmental reports (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Departmental reports (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Department and committee reports, sabbatical reports (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Department and committee reports (part) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Annual report of the placement office (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - President's report (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Department and committee reports (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Admissions reports (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Admissions: annual reports (VLB) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Admissions report (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Annual report (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Annual admissions report (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Annual admissions report (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Admissions (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Admissions report (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Admissions (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Annual admissions report (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Admissions report (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Annual admissions report (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Admissions (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Policy committee (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Policy committee (preliminary to the report) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Educational Policy Commmittee report (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Faculty: educational policy committee (Box 11, Folder 4-7)
  - Questionnaire on what students were getting from Wes experience (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Faculty: educational policy committee (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Faculty: educational policy committee (Box 12, Folder 3-5)
  - Alumni Fund (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Vanguard (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Fund Vanguard (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Army Specialized Training Program (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Assembly Series (M.A. Tuve address "Science and Humanities" (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Aviation (Box 13, Folder 6)
    (McConaughy)
  - Book Awards to Secondary Schools (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Budgets (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Centennial 1931 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Chemistry Reports (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Child Feeding Committee (Relief for children of allies) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Community Defense, air raids, etc. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut War Council (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Conscientious objectors (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Curriculum Committee (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum, Committee on Education of Scientists (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Degrees for Men in Service (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Delayed Rushing Report and Recommendations for Change (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Demopoulos, Stavros (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Distinction, Phi Beta Kappa and Sigma Xi Graduates (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Draft Deferments (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Endowment Campaign, General Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Exchange of Students (Box 14, Folder 9)
    (McConaughy), See Also: Exeter, Reed Exchange
  - Faculty Children's Exchange Scholarships (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Children's Tuition Exchange (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Finance Committee Memo (Box 14, Folder 12)
    empty
  - Faculty finance committee memo to President & board of trustees (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Faculty finance committee memo to President & board of trustees (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Faculty and Curriculum Committee of Board of Trustees (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Faculty and Curriculum Committee of Board of Trustees (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Faculty Housing (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Faculty Leaves for Service (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Ford Foundation - College Grants (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Fraternity Finances and Physical Plant (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Fraternity Situation, Trustee Minutes (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Fraternities (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Freshman Year Curriculum Committee (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Freshman Orientation Program (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Freshman Summer Term (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Division, School Services and Publications (Box 15, Folder 4-6)
  - Graduate Division, Teacher Services and Evening Seminars (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Division, Student Study (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Graduate Division, Summer School (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Humanities Reports (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Japanese-American Student Relocation Council (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Japanese Courses (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Korean Crisis (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Lawrence College, Inauguration of Nathan Marsh Pusey (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Long-Range Planning Committee (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Long-Range Planning, Department Reports (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Methodist Church (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
  - Middletown Tercentennary (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Military Conscription (Post-War) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Military Defense (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - MiscellaneousDefense (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - National Research Council (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Navy College Training Program V-12 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Navy College Training Program V-12 Contract (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Navy College Training Program V-12 Correspondence with Washington (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Navy College Training Program V-12 Selection Committee (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Navy Flight Prep School V-5, Instructors, Courses, etc., correlation w/ Wesleyan, etc. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Navy Flight Prep School V-5 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Navy Flight Prep School V-5, Cadet Regluations (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Navy Mess (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Navy Procurement V-1, V-5, V-7 Information (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - ORDWES (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - ORDWES (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Debelopment, U.S. Govt. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Principles Guiding College in Laying Plans for Educational Programs for 1943-1944 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Principles and Guidelinges for Long-range Planning (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Pullman, John S. (Trustee) Charter Amendment (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Questionnaire to Faculty (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Remedial Reading Program (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Research (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - R.O.T.C. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Salary [faculty info] (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Salary Study, comparative (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Salary Study, (for internal use) (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Faculty salaries, comparison of (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Faculty salaries (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Salary Study, comparative (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Salary Study, comparative (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Selective Service (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Service Letters (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Answers to letter 1942 June 24
  - Service Letters A-K (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Service Letters L-Z (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Social Life (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Summer Session (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - U.S.O. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Costs (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Study by Mr. Camp & Mr. Babbit
  - Trustees, Faculty and Curriculum Committee (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Trustees, Faculty and Curriculum Committee (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Veterans (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars Incident (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Visiting Professors Program (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Vocational Guidance (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Vocational Guidance Letter (Box 19, Folder 10)
    Value of Liberal Arts
  - War Manpower Commission (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Wesleyan, The Next Four Years (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Wesleyan Story of Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - The college plan - comments by outside examiners. CSS and COL (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - College plan - comments (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - College plan - COL (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - College plan - social studies (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - College plan - CQS (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - VLB's datebook (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
    Pages tied with string
  - VLB's datebooks [9 years' worth] boxes 21-24 from Box 108 (Box 21-24)
  - VLB's datebooks [9 years' worth] boxes 24-27 from Box 109 (Box 24-27)
  - 13 red, leather bound datebooks (Box 28)
  - 1 red, leather bound datebook (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: Abb -- (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: Ar -- (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: Ba -- (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: Be - Bi (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: Bla -- (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: Bu -- (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: Cad -- (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: Can -- (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: Coh -- (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: Con -- (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: Cot -- (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: Da -- (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Former faculty: De -- (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: E-- (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: F -- (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: Fisher (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: Fl -- (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Former faculty: Gall -- (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: Goo -- (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: Ha -- (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: Hew -- (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: Ho -- (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: J -- (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: Ka-Ke (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: Ki-Ky (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: L (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: Lo -- (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: Mac -- Mar (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: Mar -- (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: Mat -- (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: Me- (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: Mo -- (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: N (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Nicolson, Frank W., 1921-1941 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: N - O (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: P (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: R (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: Sa -- (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: Sc -- (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: Sh -- (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: Si -- (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: Sno -- (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: Ster -- (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: T (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: V (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Former faculty: Wa -- (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Former faculty: Wen -- (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Former faculty: Wi -- (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Former faculty: Wo -- (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Former faculty: Y & Z (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - (Past) Summer school appointments (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Fellows, the center for advanced studies: A - B (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Fellows, the center for advanced studies: C (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Fellows, the center for advanced studies: D - O (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Faculty & Center possibilities (Box 43)
  - Visiting List (Box 44)
  - A.B.C. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Association (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Complaints (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Fund (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Committee to follow the Faculty E.P.C. Report (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Secretary (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Associations A-Z (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds, Foss Hill Dormitories (Box 42, Folder 9)
    missing, orange tag inserted in place
  - Buildings and Grounds (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Chemistry Consultative Study Committee (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Colleges, General A-Z (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Kellogg, Waldo (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - A.B.C. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Association (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Complaints (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Alumni (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Alumni -- Freshman Cultivation (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Associations A-Z (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Colleges, A-Z (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut State, Department of Education (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - A.B.C. (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Alumni Complaints (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Alumni -- Adult Education Programs (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Associations (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Associations, New England Board of Higher Education (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Buildings and Grounds (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Colleges A-Z (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Connecticut Study of the Role of Public Schools (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - D.E.F.G.H. (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Graduate Division -- Evening Seminars (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Trustees -- Reorganization, 1960-1961 (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Trustees -- Reorganization of Board (Box 45, Folder 24)
  - Graduate Division -- Summer School (Box 46, Folder 1-7)
  - Library (Box 46, Folder 8-9)
  - Library (Box 46, Folder 10-11)
  - New England Conference on Graduate Education (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - New England Colleges Fund (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - New England Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Alumni -- Committee of 100 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Complaints -- Committee of 100 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Ford Foundation -- College Grants Committee (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Ford Foundation -- General Correspondence (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Gifted Child (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Fund (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Complaints (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Associations (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Associations -- Pentagonal (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Graduate Division -- School Services and Publications (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Graduate Division -- School Services (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Graduate Division -- School Services and Publications (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Division -- School Services (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Division -- School Services and Publications (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - School Services and Publications -- Minton Reports (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Graduate Division -- Teacher Services and Evening Seminars (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Institute of Ethics and Politics (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - McKinsey Report for Carnegie Corporation (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Trustees -- Faculty and Curriculum Committee (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Trustees -- Faculty and Curriculum Committee (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Trustees -- Faculty and Curriculum Committee (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - A.B.C. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - (Alumni) Association and Council (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Summer Institute (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Colleges A-Z (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - D.E.F.G.H. (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Discrimination (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Faculty -- Admissions (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Faculty -- Art Memos (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Faculty -- Astronomy (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Faculty -- Biology (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Faculty -- Chemistry (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Faculty -- E.P.C. (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Faculty -- E.P.C. (Questionnaire) (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Faculty -- English (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Faculty -- Geology (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Faculty -- German (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Faculty -- Government (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Faculty -- History (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Faculty -- Music (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Faculty -- Physical Education (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Faculty -- Physics (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Faculty -- Religion (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Faculty -- Romance Languages (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - Faculty -- Psychology (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Faculty -- Theater (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - I.J.K.L.M.N. (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - Trustees -- Buildings and Grounds (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Trustees -- Meetings (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Trustees -- Committee on Education (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Trustees -- Nominations (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Trustees -- Possibilities (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - U.V.W.X.Y.Z. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Freedom Riders (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Graduate Division -- Scholarly Books (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - O.P.Q.R.S.T. (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - President's Memo to Science Division (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Students -- Athletic Report (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Students -- College Body Senate (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Student Comments (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Students F-S (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Students W-Z (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Trustees -- Agenda (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Trustee Committees and Alumni (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Wesleyan School (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - A.B.C. (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Associations (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - D.E.F.G.H. (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Trustees -- Education Committee (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - I.J.K.L.M.N. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - O.P.Q.R.S.T. (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - U.V.W.X.Y.Z. (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - A.B.C. (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Alumni Fund (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Associations A-Na (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Associations New-Pentagonal (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Association Pentagonal - Soc. (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - D.E.F.G.H. (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - I.J.K.L.M.N. (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - O.P.Q.R.S.T. (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Science Conference (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - U.V.W.X.Y.Z. (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Wesleyan Center Fellows (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - A.B.C. (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Alumni Fund (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Associations -- American Council on Education (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Associations (Box 53, Folder 2-3)
  - Associations -- American Council of Learned Societies (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - D.E.F.G.H. (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - I.J.K.L.M.N. (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - O.P.Q.R.S.T. (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - U.V.W.X.Y.Z. (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Wes Men Abroad (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Wesleyan Center for Advanced Studies (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - A.B.C. (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Airlines (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Alumni (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Complaints (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Annuities (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Associations A-C (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Associations New-Soc. (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Associations -- American Council on Education (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Associations -- National Commission on Accrediting (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Associations -- National Commission on Accrediting (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Bequests (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Colleges (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Colleges -- University of Hartford (Box 55, Folder 5)